Contact

maludwig75@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/michaelludwig-a1b1b021 (LinkedIn) vizibility.com/MichaelALudwig (Personal) mobile.twitter.com/cypherlync (Blog)

Top Skills

A+ Certified

Desktop Support

XP

Certifications

CompTIA Network + Certification CompTIA A+ Certification

Honors-Awards

Cause For Applause

Bronze

Cause For Applause

Cause For Applause

Cause For Applause

Michael Ludwig

Information Technology Network Security Analyst Davenport, Oklahoma

Summary

My career history starts out back in 1993 when I graduated high school with a vocational certificate in Drafting and Design. I went to college part time and after 4 years of work and school took time off to decide what direction I needed to go in. I joined the U.S. Army in January of 1998 and was trained as a Electronic Switching Systems Operator/Maintainer, and was assigned to the 82nd Signal BN. I was honorably discharged in January 2002 and immediately began attending night classes for Telecommunications, so as to free up my daytime to look for a job. I was also continuing my service in the North Carolina National Guard as a commo-chief at the Butner, NC Armory. After the spring semester with no job prospects in sight I enrolled in day class during the summer, and in the fall of 2002 I switched my major to Information Systems Network Administration and Support. After the fall/spring 2002 - 2003 year I attended summer classes and decided to transfer to a combat arms unit in Southern Pines. NC. I left school and retrained to be an Armor Tanker Crewmember and was mobilized in October of 2003. I deployed to Iraq in February of 2004 and in July 2004 was medi-vaced to Germany and then to Fort Bragg where I stayed in the medical holdover program receiving care and working as a supply technician. I was medically discharged in July 2005 and started back in my major at school. I graduated in May 2006 with an A.A.S., 2 Diplomas, and 4 certificates. After working at 3 jobs that really didn't fit I found a job on Fort Bragg working with Centurum Information Technology, there I worked as a Desktop Support Technician until November 2009 when my billet was canceled. I then worked for Pomeroy IT Solutions in 2010, and then I got an opportunity to work at DellEMC in September of 2010 until I was dismissed in July 2016. I tried to start my own consulting business and was not successful. As of July 2019 I work for Osage Casino as an IT Analyst.

Experience

Osage Casino IT Analyst July 2019 - December 2019 (6 months)

Tulsa, Oklahoma

Provides 2nd level support for service requests reported to the helpdesk desk. Responsibilities include assessment, triage, research, and resolution of service requests regarding the use of application software products and/ or infrastructure components. Support includes installation, and testing of computer systems and peripherals within established standards and guidelines. Activities require interaction with application software and operating systems to diagnose and resolve unique, non-recurring problems. The position's responsibilities require independent analyses, communication and problem solving. Work is performed with little supervision and requires initiative and judgment.

Indian Health Service Security Officer March 2019 - June 2019 (4 months) Claremore, OK

Called to this service as it is related to my military experience. Patrolling facilities and/or restricting individual's access to locations for Indian Heath Services Claremore, OK. Check identification and vehicles to ensure only authorized personnel are allowed access. Secure found drugs, weapons, and contraband. Provide security and escort individuals. Perform random spot checks for compliance with key control, supply, property and vehicle security regulations and directives. Investigate minor and serious violations including some incidence of felonies. Issue verbal and written warnings to the home owners association to enforce traffic or parking regulations. Responds and reacts appropriately to hostage situations and abductions involving exercise of situational judgement.

Sunstates Security
Securty Officer
July 2018 - February 2019 (8 months)
Carolina Lakes, Arborgate Solar Farm, and CCBCC

Called to this service as it is related to my military experience. Patrolling facilities and/or restricting individual's access to locations for Carolina Lakes Property Owners Association, STRATA Solar Farm, Pittsboro & Troy, NC, and CCBC, Charlotte, NC. Check identification and vehicles to ensure only authorized personnel are allowed access. Secure found drugs, weapons, and

contraband. Provide security and escort individuals. Perform random spot checks for compliance with key control, supply, property and vehicle security regulations and directives. Investigate minor and serious violations including some incidence of felonies. Issue verbal and written warnings to the home owners association to enforce traffic or parking regulations. Responds and reacts appropriately to hostage situations and abductions involving exercise of situational judgement.

CypherLync LLC
Company Owner
July 2016 - July 2018 (2 years 1 month)
Cameron, North Carolina

Strong focus on providing a better Customer Service experiences. Oversea the IT operations for a small firearm technology company owned and operated by a disabled veteran. Troubleshooting Active Directory replication problems. Built webserver for the customer. Data center consolidation and migration. Provides technical advice and assistance to managers and staff to ensure efficient data center services, and other computer systems. Performed system imaging via Operating System Deployment (OSD) & Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager. Installation and troubleshooting of software & hardware. Created desktop images and devising a checklist for creating those images. Purchased the required IT equipment for the customers' business. Supported MAC OSX on a 15" 2011 model.

Piper Technologies - SMART IT Infrastructure Field Service Technician January 2017 - May 2017 (5 months) Wake Forest, North Carolina

Responsible for field service calls over a large geographical area to include VA, WVA, MD, PA, NC, MA, NH, & SC as to date. Responsible for company Van and its safe operation. Responsible for my own paperwork, mobile phone, laptop equipment, and home office. Trusted member of a team of professionals that have been upgrading the server equipment for Delhaize America. Responsible for upgrading the drive thru POS equipment for Sheetz. Work with Cisco 2921 E Series Servers.

Dell EMC

Principal IT Support Services Specialist - Global Client Services September 2010 - July 2016 (5 years 11 months)

Research Triangle Park, NC

Desktop Support Technician for the Apex Manufacturing Plant, Research Triangle Park Facility, and Durham Center of Excellence. Provide Customer level Desktop and Application Support services in a corporate domain environment. Provide IT related support to over 2565 end users. Responsible for triaging faulty hardware and software for customers using Windows XP ,Windows 7, and OSX. Responsible for inventory of all PC and Laptops on the corporate domain for the Apex facility to determine the scalability for the Windows 7 upgrade. Provide one on one support with the executive officers of the Apex facility, Research Triangle Park Facility, and Durham Center of Excellence in a professional manner. Keep co-workers and managers aware of any issues that would affect customer service or affect productivity. Work closely with other departments and other vendors to help provide the best support available. Made self available to provide end of quarter support. Set up presentations for conferences and all hands meetings and provide projector support. Responsible for inventory of used equipment for capital disposition and the submitting of those forms to the proper personnel. Provide support for Charlotte, NC, High Point, NC, Durham, NC, and Columbia, SC remotely in addition to supporting the Research Triangle Park Facility, and Durham Center of Excellence. Responsible for configuring Cisco Workwise and Cisco 7942 & 7965 phones using the Cisco Unified Call Manager Console. Responsible for troubleshooting Data Network connectivity issues from the workstation to the switch using proven troubleshooting techniques. Responsible for patching newly installed lines from the patch panel to the switch and contacting the NOC to get those lines activated and configured on the correct VLAN by giving them the correct switch, port, and line information. Worked with COTS. Worked with Cisco Catalyst 4500, 2600, 2950 switches.

Pomeroy
Desktop Support Specialist
January 2010 - July 2010 (7 months)
Morrisville, North Carolina

Strong focus on providing a better Customer Service experiences. Provide Desktop Support and Printer Support services to private and public sector businesses. Responsible for making repairs for customer laptop, desktop, servers and printers. Served as the Command and Control shift supervisor in a deployed environment; conducted battle tracking and mission planning and use Active Directory to set up accounts, close accounts and create new accounts for users. Responsible for service calls and maintenance for customer laptop, desktop, servers and printers. Responsible for keeping track

of my own service calls and updating all completed work using Microsoft Outlook and Excel.

Centurum Information Technology
Desktop Support Technician
November 2006 - November 2009 (3 years 1 month)

- Replaced government system desktop computers that needed life cycle replacement due to warranty expiration.
- Responsible for service calls to Active Duty, Civil Service, U.S. Army and other civilian U.S. Army contractors who need repairs for their laptop, desktop, servers and printers.
- Responsible for service calls regarding wireless LAN and network setups to the network domain.
- Responsible for keeping track of my own service calls and updating all completed work on the Remedy ISD system with incident reporting, change control, and service call follow-up.
- Granted full Administrator rights within a Microsoft Windows Networking environment for the purposes of joining PC's to a network domain.
- Experience with installing Cisco 4300 & 4500 switches in telecommunication equipment rooms.
- · Worked with COTS hardware and software.

Networx IT Business Solutions Desktop Support Technician July 2006 - October 2006 (4 months)

Repaired computers under warranty for Dell, Sony, Alien Ware, and Gateway Corporation under Unisys and Dell Decision One support. Responsible for service calls to residential and business clients who need repairs for their laptop, desktop, servers and printers. Responsible for keeping track of my own service calls and service schedule. Responsible for keeping track of my own shipping and receiving records, mileage, and hours worked using Microsoft Excel. Experience in working with customers on a day to day basis, and be able to provide them with the answer to technical questions they may have about the products. Worked with COTS hardware and software.

US Army
7 years 7 months
Assistant Supply Technician/Logistics
July 2004 - July 2005 (1 year 1 month)

Kept up with logging and ordered office supplies for Womack Army Medical Center. Worked with Microsoft Office 2003 to record and maintain lists in the Data and Records of Printer and Paper supplies. Helped keep track of what was purchased, what was deleted, and helped look-up price quotes from Boise Office Supplies. Kept track of what each department ordered for the quarter and fiscal year, and help keep track of what was on the shelf in stock.

Armor Tank Crewmenber October 2003 - July 2004 (10 months)

Deployment to Iraq for OIF where I did mounted and dismounted patrols. Set up check points. Gathered enemy intelligence. Work to earn Iraqi citizens trust and confidence in our presence.

Signal Systems Support Specialist January 2002 - October 2003 (1 year 10 months)

U.S. Army Signal Regiment, working as a Signal Systems Support Specialist-1 year. Maintains and Trouble-Shoots all Signal Communication, and Signal associated equipment assigned to the unit. Coordinates with unit Commander, and key leaders on how unit communications are to be implemented. Trained on the proper use of handling hazardous substances.

Network Switch Operator Maintainer January 1998 - January 2002 (4 years 1 month)

U.S. Army Signal Regiment, working as a Network Switching Operator/ Maintainer-4 years. Military Aircraft Radiotelephone Operator (R.T.O.) responsible for maintenance of in-flight communications. Team member responsible for network communication systems that provided voice, data, and video to key leaders and subscribers in our network area. Experienced in installing, troubleshooting, and maintaining systems control center, node center switch, extension node switches, and associated multiplexing equipment, net radio interface equipment, communications security devices(KYK-13, ANCD, and KYK-15), and transmission line of sight equipment, which are capable of processing data, voice and video. Install, set-up, and broke down Network communication equipment in accordance to company standards. Repaired circuit card assembles antenna cables, and radio cables using soldering, oscilloscope, and a multi-meter for testing. Used appropriate tools to diagnose and evaluate the cause of a network switch outage. Experienced in working with subscriber users, other team members, and higher level support to determine a strategic approach to fixing a network problem. Experienced in operating, troubleshooting, and maintaining tactical satellite radios (PSC-5, MST-20, KY-99, and KY-57). Proven ability to troubleshoot electronic equipment using and interpreting schematic diagrams, technical manuals, and experience. Experienced installing troubleshooting and maintaining equipment that utilizes Circuit Card Assembly. Worked with Cisco Catalyst 2600 Series Switches.

Education

Central Carolina Community College

Associate of Arts and Sciences (A.A.S.), Information Systems Network Administration and Support · (2001 - 2006)

NCPPSB Course

Certification NCPPSB, Security and Loss Prevention Services · (2018 - 2018)

U.S Army Signal Center and Fort Gordon

Diploma, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications · (1998 - 1998)

Pathfinder Regional Tech High

High School Diploma, CAD/CADD Drafting and/or Design Technology/ Technician · (1989 - 1993)